#### **RESUME**

#### Yi-Tsun Chen

# https://yitsunchen.herokuapp.com/

ACT, Australia

+61 (474)-429-926

chentriangoes@gmail.com

A Ph.D. graduate from the medical school of the Australian National University with expertise in conducting health research through an interdisciplinary lens and trained for outbreak investigation at the National Centre for Epidemiology and Population Health, Australia. Experienced in quality customer service and working under multiple supervisors across departments for research management ranging from proposals evaluation, grants coordination, quantitative and qualitative data analytics, and research strategies planning. Currently undertaking at a coding bootcamp in the University of Western Australia towards a certified full-stack web developer with advanced digital literacy in UI/UX design, and managing, analysing, associating, showcasing, and securing data. Experience of and advanced capacity for adopting critical, practical approaches, and languages in areas of public health, biomedicine, biology, web development, social sciences, research management to inform public health policies and programs.

# **Key Experience**

#### Employment

[2019 – 2021] Casual Grants Officer, Research Management, The Australian National University

- Grants Management and Submission
- Research Strategy Planning
- Policy and Practice Analysis
- Submission Report Analysis and Preparation

[2020 – 2021] Casual Technical Officer, Level 1 for COVID-19 Response, Canberra Health Services; ACT Government

COVID-19 Pathology

[2008 - 2009] Research Assistant, Department of Life Science, National Taiwan Normal University

- Formalise Guidelines of Standard Procedure Operation for a Molecular Imaging Lab
- Commissioning Biomedical Studies
- Digitalisation of Booking and Lab Management System
- Coordination and Delivery of Molecular Imaging Tutorial and Training Programs
- Quality Assurance and Control of Clients' Biological Specimens
- o Risk Governance to Ensure the Safety of Chemical Operations and Biosecurity
- o <u>Deliver Development Strategy for the Implementation of an Instrumentation Centre</u>

[2007 - 2008] Second Medical Lieutenant, National Service/Medical Training College, Taiwan

- Service Command
- Healthcare Management
- Preventative Medicine

#### Education

[2012 - 2020] Doctor of Philosophy, Medical School, The Australian National University

o Ph.D. Thesis: Fear of Longevity: Everyday Struggles in the Pharmaceutical Age of AIDS, Taiwan

[2011] Master of Public Health, College of Medicine, Biology and Environment, The Australian National University o GPA: 6.25/7

# Community Service

[2011 - 2015] Meridian ACT (former AIDS Action Council of the ACT)

o STRIP, Netreach, Candlelight Memorial, Out There, and more

[2011 - 2012] UnionsACT

Health Promotion Outreach

[2007 – 2013] Taiwan Tongzhi Hotline Association

o Health Education Website, Campaigns for AIDS Control and Prevention, Telephone Counsellor, Human Rights Advocacy, Volunteer(s) Training Workshops, Taiwan LGBTI Parade, and more

# **General Background**

Education

[2022 - 2023] (In Progress)

**Master of Arts** 

Applied Buddhist Studies, Nan Tien Institute

Hsing Yun Education Foundation Scholarship

[2005 – 2007] *Master of Science* 

Graduate Institute of Anatomy and Cell Biology, National Taiwan University

o GPA: 3.66/4.3

[2001 – 2005]

**Bachelor of Science** 

Department of Life Sciences, National Chung Hsing University

- o GPA: 3.19
- Chief Investigator, 'The effects on Ca2+-regulated contractile function by acidosis of skeletal and cardiac myofibrils.'

Employment

[2011 - 2021]

Casual Theatre Staff

The Australian National University

Bilingual Customer Service

[2013]

**Research Assistant** 

Institute of Ethnology, Academia Sinica, Taiwan

Literature Review of Leprosy Studies

- Fellow(s) and Memberships
  - Australian Fabians.
  - Australian Anthropological Society
  - Society for Applied Anthropology
  - Society for Social Studies of Science
  - Taiwan STS Association
  - Medical Anthropology Research Group, Institute of Ethnology, Academia Sinica, Taiwan
  - Visiting Student, Institute of Ethnology, Academia Sinica, Taiwan

# **Key Registration and Training**

- Questionnaire Design and Sampling 2.0 Workshop, Centre for Survey Research, Academia Sinica, Taiwan
- Advanced Training Certificate of Completion for Interdisciplinary AIDS Medicine and Care, Taiwan AIDS Nurses Association
- STS Summer School at Harvard
- Translator Certificate of Completion, Amnesty International Taiwan
- Training Completion of Opening up Equality in the ACT, ACT Human Rights Commission
- Science Communication Certificate of Completion, Australian National Centre for the Public Awareness of Science
- National Criminal History Check, Australian Criminal Intelligence Commission
- Working with Vulnerable People Card, Commissioner for Fair Trading, Australia

- Volunteer Facilitator Training Certificate of Completion, AIDS Action Council of the ACT
- PACT Clinic Facilitator Training Certificate of Completion,
   AIDS Action Council of the ACT
- Basic Volunteer Training Certificate of Completion, Fu-Long Volunteers Association, Taoyuan, Taiwan
- Advanced Volunteer Training Certificate of Completion,
   Fu-Long Volunteers Association, Taoyuan, Taiwan
- Professional Military Personnel (Medical Officer, Service Command; Healthcare Management Officer; Medical Staff Officer, Preventative Medicine Officer) Training Certificate of Completion, Taoyuan, Taiwan
- Certificate of Excellent Attendance in Labour Education Program, NCHU
- Web Developer Certificate Training of Coding Boot Camp, The University of Western Australia (to be completed on 30 May 2022)

## Awards, Honours, Grants and Experience

- **2022 2023** NTI Hsing Yun Education Foundation Scholarship (International Students)
- 2021 PhD Scholar Award, The Chen Clansmen Association of Dayuan
- **2021** Winner of "From across the global" of the ANU College of Science 'As You See it' Photography Competition
- **2020** ANU Gender Institute PRIZE (PhD Thesis) For Excellence in Gender and Sexuality research
- **2017 2019** ANU HDR Fee Remission Merit Scholarship
- 2018 4S Conference Travel Grant
- 2014 Studying Abroad Scholarship of Ministry of Education, Taiwan

- 2014 Overseas PhD Dissertation Scholarship in Pacific Region, Chiang Ching-Kio Foundation for International Scholarly Exchange (Withdraw)
- 2014 ANU VC Travel Grant
- 2013 Wenner-Gren Travel Award
- 2011 2012 Honour for Volunteering at Multicultural Festival of Canberra
- 2008 Excellence of Services at Combined Logistics Command, Ministry of Defence, Taiwan
- 2004 Funding for College Student Participation in Research Projects, Ministry of Science and Technology, Taiwan
- 2002 Rotary Youth Leadership Awards, Rotary International District3500

# Project(s)

Translation, Editing and Documentary
 [2022] Translator and Editor of English Subtitle for a
 Documentary Project, Take on the Streets, submitted for a Film
 Festival

[2013] Dictation Assistant for *The Yellow Birds*, Authored Kevin Powers, Translated by Jing-Xian (patient with Motor Neuron Disease) for Chinese Publication by Acropolis, Taipei

[2013] Interviewer for <u>Love Narratives: One Five and A Ten,</u> Persons with HIV/AIDS Rights Advocacy Association of Taiwan (PRAATW)

#### • Biomedical Research

[2008] Spinocerebellar Ataxia Type 17---The Development and Screening of Novel Molecules for Disease Treatment (1/3), Department of Life Sciences, National Taiwan Normal University.

[2009] SCA8 Pathogenesis: Regulation of Bidirectional Transcription, RNA Gain-Of-Function and IRES-Mediated Translation, Department of Life Sciences, National Taiwan Normal University.

# Web Development [2021 – 2022]

- Collaborative Project(s)
  - Junglr. Model View Controller
     (MVC) (Source Codes)
  - Cocktail Diversifier Server Side APIs (Source Codes)
- Independent Work(s)
  - Code Quiz\_Web APIs (Source Codes)
  - Day Planner Moment.is (Source Codes)
  - Note Taker Express.js (Source Codes)
  - <u>Text Editor\_Progressive Web</u>
     <u>Applications (PWA)</u> (Source Codes)

# Publication(s)

#### Journal Article(s)

[2017] [Review of the book Scrambling for Africa: Aids, Expertise, and the Rise of American Global Health Science, by Johanna Tayloe Crane.] East Asian Science, Technology and Society. 11 (1): 127–131.

[2011] "Quantitation of Sudomotor Innervation in Skin Biopsies of Patients with Diabetic Neuropathy." J Neuropathol Exp Neurol. 70 (10): 930-938.

[2011] "ATP13A2 variability in Taiwanese Parkinson's disease." Am J Med Genet Part B. 156:720-9.

#### • Thesis

[2007] "Quantitative Pathology of Sweat Gland Innervation in Autonomic Neuropathy: Based on Immunohistochemistry Patterns of Vasoactive Intestinal Peptide." MSc Thesis.
Graduate Institute of Anatomy and Cell Biology, Medical School, National Taiwan University.

# • International Conference(s)

**[2021]** "Everyday Struggles in Digital Age of Pandemics." In the Annual Conference of the Australian Anthropological Society, expected 30 November. Online Conference.

**[2021]** "Unsettled Boundaries: A Pandemic Tale of Three Cities between Taiwan and Australia." In the Australian Taiwanese Scholar Workshop, the Australasian Taiwan Studies Association, 26 November. Melbourne, Australia.

**[2021]** "Nationalism, the Daily of COVID-19 Prevention and Collective Memory of Trauma under the Development of Technology." In Social Pandemic: Critical Fire, Association for Taiwan Social Studies 30-31 October. Tunghai University, Taiwan.

[2021] "Collective Melancholy: Reflection on Emotions and Affections in the COVID Epidemic." In Post-COVID-19: Experiences and Exploration of Bio-Politics, Taiwan Society for Medical Anthropology, 2 October. Institute of Ethnology, Academia Sinica, Taiwan (Panel Moderator).

**[2021]** "AIDS Governance in Taiwan through the Lens of Multi-hyphenate Anthropology." In Queer Asia as Method Conference, 11 September. King's College London.

**[2019]** "The Way of Facing AIDS." In Inaugural HDR Symposium, ANU Medical School, 29 November. aMBUSH The Australian National University.

# **Public Engagement(s)**

#### Community Service(s)

#### [Association for Taiwan Social Studies]

Panellist for the 2021 PhD Thesis Competition

## [Nan Tien Institute] Wollongong

- Communities of Practice
- Assistant for Studies on Humanistic Buddhism

#### [Refugee Action Campaign] ACT

Townhall Meeting

## [Amnesty International] ACT/SNSW

- o End Child Labour on Palm Oil Plantation
- ACT Indigenous Rights Group

## [Taiwanese Association of Canberra]

- Multicultural Festival
- Fundraising

# [Buddha's Light International Association]—Young Adult Division, Taoyuan, Taiwan

Miscellaneous Activities

## [Vision Youth Action] Taiwan

- o English Education to Indigenous Community
- Environmental Conservation and Sustainability

## Guest Speaker(s)/Lecturer(s)

[2021] "Wearing Mask: Meaning under the Intersection of Science, Society and Culture." In the Class of Advanced Language, expected 24 November. Municipal Wu-Ling Senior High School, Taiwan.

**[2021]** "Gay Identity in Taiwan: From Queer Rebels to Pharmaceutical Conformists." In Meeting of the AIDS Group, 7 May. Tongzhi Hotline Association, Taiwan.

[2014] "Social Side Effects of Triple Cocktail Therapy." In Contemporary Health Issues of MPH, 23 October. College of Medicine, Biology and Environment, The Australian National University, Australia.

[2013] "Chores Servant – Trick at Front Stage and Strategy at Back Stage for the Survival among HIV/AIDS Infected." In Wednesday Lunch Seminar, 18 December. Institute of Ethnology, Academia Sinica, Taiwan.